JOSHUA T. GUERIN | Curriculum Vitae

✓ jguerin@utm.edu • Martin, TN • J (859) 576-2726 G GitHub • in LinkedIn • G Facebook

SUMMARY & SKILLS _____

Computer Science Professor

Al Specialist

Competitive Strongman

SPECIALIZED SKILLS Answer Set Programming | Knowledge Representation and Reasoning

Logic Foundations of Al Logical & Functional Programming | SAT Solvers PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE **Experienced:** C | C++ | Clingo (Answer-Set Dialect) | Haskell | Java | Python

Familiar: Javascript | Lisp | Matlab | Perl | PHP | Prolog | R | Shell Scripting | SQL

FRAMEWORKS & TOOLS Docs Generators | Git | Graphviz/DOT Language | LATEX | Unix CLI

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF KENTUCKY Lexinaton, KY

Ph.D., Computer Science 2012

Dissertation

Graphical Models for Decision Support in Academic Advising.

Relevant Coursework

Algorithm Design | Artificial Intelligence | Bayesian Al Boolean Functions | Data Mining

Database Systems | Declarative Programming

Programming Languages

M.S., Computer Science 2010 Graduate Certificate, Cognitive Science 2009

TRANSYLVANIA UNIVERSITY

Lexinaton, KY B.A., Computer Science 2002-2006

Minor: Psychology

Experience _____

UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE AT MARTIN Martin, TN Professor 2021-present **Department Chair** 2018-2021 2017-2018 Interim Department Chair Associate Professor 2016-2021 **Assistant Professor** 2012-2016

UNIVERSITY OF KENTUCKY Lexington, KY Research Fellowship 2012 Lexington Herald-Leader Research Fellowship

TRANSYLVANIA UNIVERSITY Lexington, KY Part-Time Instructor Fall 2011

UNIVERSITY OF KENTUCKY Lexington, KY 2007-2011 Teaching & Research Assistant

Example projects/code _____

DPLL

All examples are available on https://github.com/joshuaguerin.

• A Haskell implementation of the DPLL algorithm for CNF satisfiability.

DOOMNT

• An Emacs extension for automatic/interactive generation of function, class, and file documentation.

KATTIS SOLUTIONS

• A set of solutions for problems on the competitive programming site open.kattis.com/.

Example courses taught _____

UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE AT MARTIN

2012-Present

Algorithm Design and Analysis • Artificial Intelligence • Intro to C++ Autonomous Mobile Robotics • Computer Graphics • Data Structures Discrete Mathematics • Microcontrollers Lab • Object-Oriented Programming Programming Language Paradigms • Senior Capstone Project/Career Preparation Theory of Computation • Quantum Programming